[{"question":"<p><strong>A motorist drives for 2hr at 100km\/h. What is her average speed in km\/h?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["88","90","100","None of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ratio of the weight lifted to the force applied is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mechanical advantage","velocity ration","efficiency","work output"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The correct expression for radical acceleration is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["V<sup>2<\/sup>\/r","MV<sup>2<\/sup>","MV<sup>2<\/sup>\/r","M<sup>2<\/sup>V<sup>2<\/sup>\/r"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>How much work must be done to stretch a spring by 2cm if the spring constant is 640N\/m?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8.40J","9.40J","10.40J","0.128J"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the photon energies in joules in red light of wavelength 7.0 x 10<sup>-7<\/sup>m. (take h = 6.63 x 10<sup>-34<\/sup>J.S , C = 3.0 X 10<sup>8<\/sup> )<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.9 x 10<sup>-19<\/sup>J","6.6 x 10<sup>-16<\/sup>J","2.8 x 10<sup>-19<\/sup>J","2.8 x 10<sup>-16<\/sup>J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A heater resistor of 100\u2126 has an a.c of 2.82A peak flowing through it. Calculate the power dissipated.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["400W","500W","600W","800W"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a projectile motion, the expression for time of flight is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2Usin\u03b8) \/ g","(U<sup>2<\/sup>Sin2\u03b8) \/ g2g","(U<sup>2<\/sup>Sin<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8) \/ g","(U<sup>2<\/sup>sin\u03b8) \/ 2g"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which particle is not affected by a magnetic or an electric field?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Electron","Proton","Neutron","Beta-particle"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mirage is an example of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["reflection of light","diffraction of light","polarization","total internal reflection"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A boy drops a stone from the top of a building and sees it hit the ground 3s later. From this he concluded that the height of the building was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["29.4m","88.1m","45m","88.5m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pairs are measured in the same units?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["momentum and energy","momentum and work","momentum and impulse","momentum and power"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The refractive index of a certain medium with respect to air is 1.35. If the speed of light in air is 3 x 10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s, calculate the speed of light in the medium<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.5 x 10<sup>7<\/sup>m\/s","4.05 x 10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s","2.2 x 10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s","4.35m\/s"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two mirrors are placed at right angles and an object is placed between them 30mm from one and 40mm from the other. The number of images will be<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The iris of the human eye&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["has no practical use","contracts when we view objects close to the eye","regulate the amount of light entering the eye","helps to clean the eye"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not electrical unit?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ampere","coulomb","ohm","resistivity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An electric lamp is marked 240V, 60W. It is left to operate for 1 hour. How much heat is generated by the lamp?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60J","3600J","216000J","900J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the current that flows in a 4<\/strong><b>\u2126<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;resistor for 25s to generate 10,000J of energy<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10A","100A","31.62A","62.25A"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is the correct order of magnitude of wavelengths, starting with the smallest?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["X-rays, infra red, visible spectrum, ultra violet, radio waves","X-rays, radio waves, infra red, visible spectrum, ultra violet","X-rays, ultra violet, infra red, visible spectrum, radio waves","X-rays, ultra violet, visible spectrum, infra red, radio waves"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In order to mark the upper fixed point on a centigrade thermometer, the thermometer is placed in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["boiling water","steam","hot water","just above boiling water"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The coefficient of linear expansion of brass is approximately 0.00002\/C. Therefore, if 1000mm<sup>3<\/sup> of brass is heated from 0k to 30k, it expands by what amount ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.6mm<sup>3<\/sup>","0.2mm<sup>3<\/sup>","1.8mm<sup>3<\/sup>","0.06mm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The number of joules necessary to change the temperature of 40g of water from 15<\/strong><b>\u00b0<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">C to 65<\/strong><b>\u00b0<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">C is?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p><p><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">(specific heat capacity of water = 4200 J\/kg.C)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["168","2110","2000","8400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The split ring cummutator which is found on an electric motor is used to&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["keep the current which flows into the coil constant","change alternating current to direct current","keep the field strength constant","reserve the current in the coil as it turns"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A shunt is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a high resistance connected in series with an ammeter","a low resistance connected in parallel with a voltmeter","a high resistance connected in series with a voltmeter","a low resistance connected in parallel with an ammeter"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A person is 5ft 8in tall, express this height in metres<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.73m","1.83m","1.93m","2.73m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><b>A golf ball hit an angle of&nbsp;<span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">30<\/span><sup style=\"font-size: 10.5px;\">o<\/sup><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;<\/span>above horizontal with a speed of 44m\/s. How high does it rise?<\/b><\/p>","options":["2.24m","24.7m","171m","34.3m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If body A pulls or pushes on body B, then body B also pulls or pushes on body A. The force on each body has the same magnitude, but the forces are oppositely directed is a statement of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Newton's first law of motion","Newton's second law of motion","Newton's third law of motion","Newton's law of gravitation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>How much work must be done to stretch a spring by 2cm if the spring constant is 640N\/m<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.64J","0.128J","0.84J","0.94J"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><b>A logger drags a heavy log across level ground by attaching a cable from the log to a bulldozer. The cable is inclined upward from horizontal at an angle 20\u00b0, the cable exerts a constant force of 2000 N while pulling the log 16 m. How much work is done in dragging the log?<\/b><\/p>","options":["3 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>J","4 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>J","5 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>J","6 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>J"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man pushes at constant speed a 50kg refrigerator a distance of 14m across a level floor where the coefficient of friction is 0.4. How much work is done?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2720J","2725J","2750J","2735J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A crate is sitting in the centre of a flat bed truck. The truck accelerates to the right and the crates moves with it, what is the direction of frictional force exerted by the truck in the crate?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["to the left","to the right","no frictional force because the crate is not sliding","both left and right"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the work done by a man on the vacuum cleaner if he pulls it 3m with a horizontal force of 32N<\/strong><\/p>","options":["130J","16J","50J","None of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mattress of a water bed is 2m long by 2m wide and 30cm deep. Find the weights of the water in the mattress<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.20 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>N","1.18 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>N","2.95 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>N","8.9 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>N"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A parallel capacitor has plates of dimensions 2cm by 3cm separated by a 1mm thickness of paper, find its capacitance . ( take&nbsp;<\/strong><b>\u0190o = 8.85 x 10\u207b\u00b9<\/b><b style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">\u00b2<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">) .<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20 x 10<sup>-12<\/sup>F","30 x 10<sup>-12<\/sup>F","40 x 10<sup>-12<\/sup>F","50 x 10<sup>-12<\/sup>F"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following has the greatest ionizing power?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["alpha particles","beta particles","gamma rays","neutron"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"}]